Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory10 Mss.B.B61.inventory10
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (N-Q)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory10
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents N
  - Nachbin, J. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 16; 2p.
  - Nacht, Ray (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 May 3; 1p.
      Scope and Contents note
      (Enc: Re visits to the Soviet Union)
  - Nadejena, Lydia (Mrs. Krinken) (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1942 June 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - (Enc: Morey, Charles R. (open letter), Varney, John (open Letter), 1942 Dec. (end)
    - Lydia Nadejena -- to Harriet Moore, 1942 Apr. 17; 1p.
  - Naetebus (Box 65)
    - Naetebus -- to Germanistic Society, 1920 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - Naetebus -- to Germanistic Society, 1920 Dec. 15; 1p.
  - Nagel, Charles (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 9; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 June 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 8; 1p.
  - Nagel, Louis (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 20; 3p.
  - Nagle, A. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 6; 1p.
  - Nahon, Zarita (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1934 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Nov. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 July 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 May 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1937 July 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 July 11; 2p.
  - Nakamusa, Yasuma (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 23; 5p.
  - Nakano, Kenneth M. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - (Enc: Japanese Comm. for Democracy. Constitution and Newsletter.), 1942 Mar. 18; 1p.
  - Nakaya, J. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 25; 2p.
  - Nansen, Fridtjof (Box 65)
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from A.W. Brogger, 1926 Apr. 12
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from C.A. Buturlin, 1926 Nov. 9
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from S.A. Buturlin, 1927 Jan. 24; 9p.
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from S.A. Buturlin, 1927 May 3
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- to The Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture, 1926 Apr. 12; 15p.
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from M. Litvinoff, 1926 Aug. 24
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- to M. Litvinoff, 1926 Aug. 31; 1p.
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from K. Nielsen, 1926 Apr. 11
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from K. Nissen, 1926 Apr. 12
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from K.E. Schreiner, 1926 Apr. 12
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from P. Smidowitch, 1927 Oct. 27
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- from L. Tchitcherin, 1926 July 23
    - Fridtjof Nansen -- to L.Tchitcherin, 1926 June 25; 2p.
  - Narayan, J.P. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 14; 2p.
  - Nash, Francis S. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1885 Mar. 13
  - Nash, Jay B. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1938 June 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 July 14; 1p.
  - Nash, John McLean (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1910 Aug. 2
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 22
    - To Boas, 1910 May 13
    - To Boas, 1910 July 5
    - John McLean Nash -- to F.P. Keppel, 1909 Apr. 14
  - Nassau, Robert H. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 26
    - From Boas, 1917 June 22
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 27
    - To Boas, 1917 June 14
    - To Boas, 1917 June 26
    - Robert H. Nassau -- to H.A. Andrew, 1917 June 26
  - Nathan, Otto (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 27; 1p.
  - Nation, The (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1903 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Oct. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919? Oct.??; 2p.
    - (see Boas to Cattell, J.M., Oct.8, 1919)
    - From Boas, 1922 Dec. 9; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - See Marshall, Margaret -, 6-4-36 6-11-36
      See Kirchwey, Freda
      See Villard, Oswald Garrison
  - National Academy of Sciences* (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. (end)
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. (end)
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. (end)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 23
    - See Brickett, Paul, (3-20-36, 3-24, 3-26, 4-8-36)
    - See Lillie, Frank R., (3-12-36)
    - See Pearl, Raymond, (11-9-33)
    - National Academy of Sciences -- from R.S. Woodworth:, 1933 Nov. 24, 1934 Oct. 11 and Nov. 1
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr.9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar.23; 1p.
  - National City Bank (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 9; 1p.
  - National Committee For The Defense of Political Prisoners (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 31
    - See Solow, H. Dec. 28, 1932, 1934 Aug. 2; 2p.
    - (Enc. with Hirsch, A.H., Aug. 13, 1934)
  - National Conference on the Christian Way of Life (Box 65)
    - See Lasker, B., Feb. 23, 1925
  - National Coordinating Comm., 1938 Jan 3 (Box 65)
  - National Council for Pan-American Democracy (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 23; 2p.
  - National Council of Jewish Women of America (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 23; 1p.
  - National Emergency Conference (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1939 May 13; 4p.
    - To Boas (open letter), 1939 June 22; 2p.
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties (Box 65)
    - See Boas, F. Notes re... attached to Conal, B., 1941 Feb. 20
  - National Free Browder Congress (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 23; 1p.
  - National German American Alliance (Box 65)
    See Hexamer, C. J.
  - National Institute of Social Sciences (Box 65)
    - N.I.S.S. -- from E. Rodakiewicz, 1917 May 11
  - National Museum of Canada (Box 65)
    - National Museum of Canada -- from Barbeau, M., 1938 Feb. 9
    - (Enc. with Barbeau, M., Feb. 10, 1938)
  - National Non-Partisan League (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1919 Sept. 8; 1p.
  - National Research Council (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1918 Mar. 9; 3p.
      (as member of committee)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 27; 1p.
  - National Research Council (Box 65)
    See Angell, James R.
    - See Britton, N.L. to Gates, F.T., 1918 Mar. 10
    - NRC -- from Robert H. Lowie, 1932 Jan.20
    - NRC -- from Robert H. Lowie, 1932 Jan.22
    - NRC -- from Robert H. Lowie, 1932 Feb.4
    - NRC -- from Robert H. Lowie, 1932 Feb.18
    - NRC -- from Robert H. Lowie, 1932 Apr.14
    - NRC -- from Vernon Kellogg, 1930 May, 3
    - NRC -- from Vernon Kellogg, 1930 May 17
    - NRC -- from Vernon Kellogg, 1930 May 19
    - NRC -- from Duncan S. Johnson, 1932 May 12
    - NRC -- from Albert L. Barrows, 1932 Dec.10
    - NRC -- from Albert L. Barrows, 1932 Dec.14
  - National Research Council- Board of Biological Sciences (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 12; 1p.
  - National Research Council Child Development (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 31; 1p.
  - National Research Council -- Circular no. 9 (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1931 Sept.10; 2p.
  - National Research Council - Committee on Fellowships (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1923 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 11; 2p.
  - National Research Council - Div. of Anthropology and psych. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug.2-20; 27p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 19; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar.; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec.
    - NRC -- from W.V. Bingham, 1919 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - NRC -- from A.V. Kidder, 1926 Oct. 30
  - National Research Council - Executive Board (Box 65)
    - NRC -- from V. Kellogg, 1931 Jan. 26
    - NRC -- from V. Kellogg, 1931 June 3
  - National Research Council -- Inquiry on research on the young child (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 18; 1p.
  - National Resources Committee (Box 65)
    - See Lorimer, Frank -, 6-23-36, 6-26-36, 7-1-36
  - Nationality Differences in the use of Symbolic and Pantomimic Gestures (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 7; 3p.
      See Gestures, Scenario Draft
  - Natorp, Paul (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1921 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 5; 3p.
  - Naumberg, Aaron (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 14; 1p.
  - Navioneb(?), Simon (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 29
  - Nazis, Report (Box 65)
    Full title of document: "Report on Progress of Public Statement of Scientists in Condemnation of Nazis".
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 27; 4p.
      (Enc: Estimate for finishing the present circular. 1p.)
  - Neare, Lucia (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 27; 1p.
  - Nebehay, Carl (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 27; 5p.
  - Necker, Arthur L. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 13; 1p.
  - Nederlandsch Comité (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov.
    - (Enc. in Liagre, A. de, Jan. 17, 1925.)
  - Neef, Adolf K. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 18; 1p.
  - Neff, Mary Lawson (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 27
    - To Boas, 1912 Nov. 24; 2p.
  - Negro - Mental Characteristics (Box 65)
    - See Boas, F, to Crane, R.T., Oct. 5, 1932
  - Neibling, Harold E. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1931 May 11; 2p.
  - Neifert, Josiah Martyn (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1916 Sept. 18
    - To Boas, 1917 June 23
  - Neikel, Gustav -- To Boas, 1912 May 17 (Box 65)
  - Neilson, H.P. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 15
    - To Boas, 1932 July 8
  - Neilson, John (Box 65)
    - John Neilson -- to J.A. Teit, 1918 Apr. 10; 1p.
  - Neilson, W.A. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1919 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept.3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 16; 1p.
    - See McConnell, F.J., 1939 Jan. 25
    - W.A. Neilson -- from A. Hrdlicka, 1939 Dec. 20
    - (Enc. with Conal, Bernard, Dec.26, 1939)
  - Neissen, H. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1939 July 28; 1p.
  - Neisser, W. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 29; 1p.
  - Nelles, Walter, R. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 9
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 6
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 4
  - Nelson, Dr. Boris E. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1929 May 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar.1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar.4; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept.13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 4; 1p.
  - Nelson, E.G. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - E.G. Nelson -- to R.W. Bryan, 1932 Aug. 6; 1p.
  - Nelson, N.C. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 July 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 18; 1p.
  - Nelson, T. and Sons (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 4; 1p.
  - Nelson, W. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 11
  - Nelson, W.S. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1930 May 23; 1p.
  - Nernst, Walter (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 17; 1p.
  - Neuberger, Mrs.B. -- from Boas, 1910 Aug.13 (Box 65)
  - Neue Volkszeitung. Editor (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 23; 1p.
  - Neugass, E. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 17
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 15
  - Neuhausen, Nellie (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1939 July 27; 1p.
  - Neuhausen, S. A. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 30; 1p.
  - Neuhsaus (?), P. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1929 July 4; 1p.
  - Neuken, Jules (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1920 Dec. 26; 2p.
  - Neulder, R. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1907 May 31
  - Neumann, Fritz (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 1; 2p.
  - Neumann, Gerhardt (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 20; 1p.
  - Neumann, John von (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 8; 1p.
  - Neumann, Leopold (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p.
  - Neumann, W. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1925 Nov. 23; 1p.
  - Neumayer, Georg von (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1885 June 29
    - To Boas, 1885 May 11; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1886 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1886 Mar. 28
    - To Boas, 1886 July 1
    - To Boas, 1896 July; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Sept. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Sept.17; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 July 15; 1p.
  - Neunmeister, K. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 16; 2p.
  - Neustaetter, Otto (Box 65)
    - From Boas
    - See Boas to Czellitzer & Neustaetter, 1926 Feb. 15
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept.27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Aug. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 15
    - (see Czellitzer & Neustaetter), 1940 Sept. 19; 2p.
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1942 Oct. 14; 1p.
  - "A New Day for the Indian" -- Pamphlet (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. end; 1p.
  - New Era Printing Company (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 22
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 27
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 16
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 6
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 22
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 30
    - From Boas, 1917 May 18
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Sept.10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 Sept.25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1900 Sept.29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. end; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 11
    - (see Riesberg, F. W. Apr.11,1918), 1920 Sept.8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept.30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - New Era Printing Co. -- from M. A. Andrews, 1913 May 28
    - New Era Printing Co. -- from H.A. Andrews, 1920 Sept.17; 1p.
    - New Era Printing Co. -- to McGee, J.W., 1899 July 15; 4p.
    - New Era Printing CO. -- to Peabody, C., 1914 Dec. 29
  - New Jersey Citizens Committee -- to Free Earl Browder (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 1; 1p.
  - New Republic (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 31; 1p.
      See Cowley, Malcolm
      See Coutwell, Robert
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - New School for Soc. Res. follows N.Y. World Tel New World Settlement Fund (Box 65)
    - (Enc. with Villard, O.G., July 1, 1940)
  - New York academies follow New York State New York Board of Ed. Board of Examiners, Modern Language Div. (Box 65)
    - See Bonaschi, Alberto C.-, 6-12-36
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 23; 1p.
  - New York Board of Higher Education (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 23; 2p.
    - (Enc. with Tead, O., Mar. 5,1940)
  - New York Bureau of Educational Experiments (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1926 May 4; 1p.
  - New York City, Bureau of Vital Statistics (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 4; 1p.
  - New York City. Commissioner of Hospitals (Box 65)
    See Fay, James H.
  - New York City, Department of Education (Box 65)
    See Robinson, Anna E.
  - New York City, Department of Hospitals (Box 65)
    - See Fleming, Mark L. to Boas, Ernst P. -, dated 10-17-33
  - New York City, German Consulate General (Box 65)
    See Drechler, D.
    See Gneist
    See Lewinski, Karl von
    See Luetkens, Gerhart
    See Reichel, G. A.
    See Reinhardt, Walter
    See Wulfing, John
  - New York City, Museum of the American Indian (Box 65)
    See Hodge, F. W.
  - New York City, Museum of Natural History (Box 65)
    See Osborn, Henry Fairfield
  - New York City National Coordinating Committee (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan. 3; 1p.
  - New York City, The "Palisadian" (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 19; 2p.
  - New York City. Police Commissioner (Box 65)
    See Fowler, Harold
  - New York City, Post Office, Station J (Box 65)
  - New York City, Post Office Inspector (Box 65)
    See Battles, C. A.
  - New York City, Public Library (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Dec. end; 10p.
    - To Boas, 1932 June 6
  - New York City, Public School No. 821 (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1909 June 22; 2p.
  - New York City, "Springfield Republican" (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 31; 3p.
  - New York City, Surrogates' Court (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 14
  - New York Corn Exchange Bank (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 8; 1p.
  - New York Court of General Sessions (Box 65)
    See Halpern, Irving W.
  - New York State (Box 65)
    - See Malzberg, Benjamin -, 6-23-36, 6-29-36
  - New York State, Department of Mental Hygiene (Box 65)
    See Malzberg, Benjamin
  - New York State Training School for Girls (Box 65)
    - See Morse, Fannie French-, 2-7-35, 2-12-35, 2-19-35
  - New York Academy of Anthropology (Box 65)
    See Catschet, Albert S.
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 65)
    See Lewinski Corwin, E. H.
  - New York Academy of Medicine, Librarian (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 9
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1888 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 1
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 2
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 7; 2p.
    - New York Academy of Sciences -- from M. Camunas, 1917 Aug. 21
  - New York Academy of Sciences - Minutes of Meeting (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1915 Jan. 28
  - New York Academy of Sciences - Porto Rico Committee (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1915 Sept. 1; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 17; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 22; 2p.
      - From Britton, N.L., 1921 Dec. 5
    - New York Academy of Sciences-Porto Rico Committee -- from N.L. Britton, 1925 Jan. 13
  - New York College Teachers Union (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Boas, F. to Lombardo, C.J., Oct. 14, 1940)
    - New York College Teachers Union -- from A.J. Kraus, May 20, 1940
    - (Enc. with Kraus, A.J., May 22, 1940)
  - New York Committee to Aid Victims of German Fascism (Box 65)
  - New York Conference for Inalienable Rights
    - See Boas, F. Notes...Attached to Conal, B., Feb. 20, 1941
  - New York Evening Journal (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1916 Sept.29
  - New York Evening Mail (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar.30; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 3
  - New York Evening Post (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 5
    - From Boas, 1919 May 8; 5p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Nov. 3; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - (Enc. Boas, F. to Hull, Cordell, Nov. 27, 1941)
    - (Enc. Boas, F. to Henry-Haye, G. Nov. 27, 1941), 1942 Oct. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - New York Evining Post -- from J.M. Cattell, 1917 June 26
    - New York Evening Post -- from A. Diaz Carcia, 1937 Oct. 11
    - (Enc. with Carcia Diaz, A., Oct.12, 1937)
  - New York Foundation (Box 66)
    - 1935 Aug. 8, 2p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 25; 3p.
    - See Fuerst, William F.-, 8-8-35
    - See Heyman, David M.-, 9-20-35, 9-26-35, 9-30-35, 10-1-35, 10-3-35
    - See Waaland, H.-, 8-9-35
    - See Warburg, Felix-, 7-15-35
  - New York Herald (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1900 Sept.30; 1p.
  - New York Herald-Tribune (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 2
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 2
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - New York Life Insurance Co. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1900 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - New York Life Insurance Co. -- from F. Reiche, 1929 Oct. 16
    - (Enc. with Reiche, F., Oct. 27, 1929)
  - New York Peace Committee (Box 66)
    - See Boas, F. to C.H. Van Tyne, enc., Apr. 4, 1940
  - New York Sun (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept.20; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1938 May 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - New York Sun -- from E.?I.? Fenlon, 1937 Sept.23
  - New York Sunday Times (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1914 Oct. 17 and Nov. 10
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 9
    - From Boas, 1916 Mar. 18
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 9; 1p.
  - New York Times, Editor (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1916 Mar. 15
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 13
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Oct. 29; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Nov. 5
    - From Boas, 1924 Apr. 9; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1924 May 20; 6p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 24and Dec. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept.7; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Aug. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Oct. 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Mar. 18
    - To Boas, 1933 July 21
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. to N.Y. Post, Nov.27, 1941.
    - New York Times -- from Dearborn, N.H., 1941 Nov. 6
    - New York Times -- from Garcia Diaz, A., 1937 Oct. 10
    - (Enc. with Garcia Dias, A., Oct. 12, 1937)
    - New York Times -- from Rosenfeld, Kurt, 1942 Dec. 22
    - (Enc. with Rosenfeld, Kurt to Boas, E.P., Dec. 22, 1942)
    - See Garbedian, H. Gordon-, 4-21-36
    - See Kaempffert, Waldemar-etc., 4-21-36
  - New York Tribune (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1921 Jan. 19; 2p.
    - See Boas, F. to N.Y. Post, Nov. 27, 1941.
  - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1932 Mar. 20; 1p.
      See Goldberg, Jacob A.
  - New York University, Council for Student Equality (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 22; 1p.
  - New York University, Division of General Education (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 11; 1p.
  - New York University, Graduate Fellowship Committee (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1936 Feb. 25; 1p.
      See Mandel, John R.
  - New York University & Bellevue Hospital. New Yorker Staats-Zeitung (Box 66)
    - 1916 Mar. 15
    - From Boas, 1919 May 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933? Dec. end